<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<name>Håkon Skjelten</name>
		<email>skjelten@pvv.org</email>
	</maintainer>
	<maintainer type="project">
		<name>Proxy Maintainers</name>
		<email>proxy-maint@gentoo.org</email>
	</maintainer>
	<longdescription lang="en">
	EmuSC is a software synthesizer that aims to emulate the Roland Sound Canvas SC-55 lineup to recreate
	the original sounds of these '90s era synthesizers. Emulation is done by extracting relevant information
	from the original control and PCM ROMs and reimplement the synth's behavior in modern C++.

	This project has been in development since 2022 and is currently able to reproduce audio that is relatively
	similar to the original synths. There are still some significant shortcomings in the generated audio,
	varying on which instruments and settings are being used, but the goal is to be able to reproduce sounds
	that will make it very difficult to notice the difference.

	If you are looking for the best possible SC-55 emulation today you might want to try
	<pkg>media-sound/nuked-sc55</pkg>, or to use a sound font based on the SC-55, such as SC-55 sound font
	made by Kitrinx and NewRisingSun.

	The EmuSC project is split into two parts:
		<pkg>media-sound/libemusc</pkg>: A library that implements all the Sound Canvas emulation.
		<pkg>media-sound/emusc</pkg>: A desktop application that serves as a frontend to libEmuSC.

	Note that this project is in no way endorsed by or affiliated with Roland Corp.
	</longdescription>
	<longdescription lang="ru">
	EmuSC - программа синтеза звука, которая эмулирует MIDI модуль Roland Sound Canvas SC-55 и совместимые
	с ним, воссоздавая оригинальное звучание этих винтажных синтезаторов 1990-х.
	EmuSC спроектирована на основе информации. полученной из анализа прошивок оригинальных устройств,
	и детвльно воспроизводит поведение синтезатора на языке C++.

	Проект назодится в разработке с 2022 года, и уже способен выдавать звук, достаточно похожий
	на оригинал, хотя в некоторых ситуациях ещё заметны недостатки, зависящие от используемых инструментов
	и настроек. Несмотря на это, цель проекта - генерировать звучание, максимально неотличимое от звучания
	реального устройства.

	Если Вы ищете наиболее точную эмуляцию SC-55 на сегоднящний день, попробуйте <pkg>media-sound/nuked-sc55</pkg>.
	Также Вам может подойти библиотека патчей (sound font) на основе звуков SC-55,например от Kitrinx
	и NewRisingSun.

	Проект состоит из двуз частей:
		<pkg>media-sound/libemusc</pkg>: Ядро эмуляции - разделяемая библиотека без внешних зависимостей.
		<pkg>media-sound/emusc</pkg>: Приложение пользователя - графическая обёртка над ядром эмулятора.

	Проект EmuSC никоим образом не одобрен, не поддерживается и не связан с компанией Roland Corp.
	</longdescription>
	<use>
		<flag name="wav">Support saving to WAV file format.</flag>
		<flag name="lfomonitor">Enable LFOs and envelopes monitor based on QtCharts.</flag>
		<flag name="qtmultimedia">Build QtMultimedia audio backend.</flag>
	</use>
	<upstream>
		<maintainer status="active">
			<name>Håkon Skjelten</name>
			<email>skjelten@pvv.org</email>
		</maintainer>
		<changelog>https://github.com/skjelten/emusc/releases</changelog>
		<doc lang="en">https://github.com/skjelten/emusc/wiki</doc>
		<bugs-to>https://github.com/skjelten/emusc/issues</bugs-to>
		<remote-id type="github">skjelten/emusc</remote-id>
	</upstream>
</pkgmetadata>